hi guys so I don't have a clue how to
work this thing so I'm trying to figure
out how to use it right now in real time
YouTube has a wonderful opportunity to
just let me do it right in front of the
entire universe penalty say so here's
the deal I've been having an enormous
number of conversations over the past
two weeks and I wanted to make something
more shared because it's hard to have
this conversation over and over again so
here's the deal
a very important frame that needs to be
held as widely as possible is this
notion of a meta crisis what we're
dealing with right now can really only
be grasped fully as we if we understand
it in that fashion so here's what I mean
we have a lot of different kinds of
systems that are always of course
interrelating with each other so you
know the the economic system which is to
say that the thing that is associate
with people actually doing those stuff
in the world is connected to the
financial system they're not the same
thing they're connected but also say for
example the medical system so that if
the system that provides medical
services is a part of the economy and
there's also influence know by things
aren't necessarily strictly medical like
for example if a if a hospital goes
bankrupt that interrupts the service of
medicine to people even though it has
nothing to do with the doctors nurses
and people all right that's like a
general sense in terms of us having
right now in the coronavirus we need to
really grasp the the magnitude and the
impact of the set of systems that are
interrelated and are impacting each
other and how those impacts cross over
to really be able to handle and get a
sense of what's happening and what will
continue to unfold so let's just start
with the medical alright so well the
medical what I mean is is the virus
itself right there's a huge amount of
information that's now being pushed out
on all kinds of channels and there's a
lot of noises and we should be clear the
reality is there's a lot of stuff we
don't know there's a lot of stuff that
is based at the wrong epistemological
models or it may be bad agendas
nonetheless we are getting better and
better and faster and faster getting a
sense of saying what's the current state
of the number of cases that have been
tested using our limited testing
methodology to different locations
according the reporting that the dollars
of those locations use we can talk about
things like
the an increasingly rich amount of
scientific literature on the specific
etiology of the virus the for example
the degree to which is susceptible is
not susceptible to heat etc this is all
good stuff this is all under the heading
of medical I so under the medical
heading we've got a giant pile of things
who can understanding the epidemiology
how it spreads thinking about the
various kinds of interventions we can
engage in the impact of different kinds
of quarantines the impact of different
kinds of I think it's not called social
distancing or now it's called physical
distancing the impact you know does it
matter whether you talk about different
age groups and all this stuff right all
these things are happening inside this
subset of medical epidemiology
quarantine inside medical also inside
medical are things like how do we deal
with the actual treatment like when
somebody comes down with this what did
the how does it show up in the body what
are the arcs what kinds of treatments
can be handled by people at home what
kind of treatments require medical
personnel when you're in the medical
environment what are the magnitudes of
treatments you have to deal with